let's do 21 meditation 21 we're going to
finish I'm sure Oh 9:30 I'll give you a
break six more minutes okay all right I
keep remembering this advice from the
most popular teacher at Princeton they
interviewed him and he said the main
thing is let students out early they
will love you even if it's two minutes
three minutes I'm just telling you guys
teacher trick good teacher training let
your students out early are you hot
anymore how many people warm raising him
how many people not don't want to
air-conditioning Ranger Tim okay you win
recently I was out with the day I went
to church and I promised myself a good
breakfast out you know at a restaurant
if I went to church because you have to
get up you have to get up early
this is how my mom used to bribe me to
go to church and I went to church and
then it ended early and there is no good
restaurant wearing there on Sunday
nothing you know I even went to the
casino and I said you guys have been to
Branson like no like alright then that
that Phil knows the place El Patio that
we got we have a little Mexican
restaurant trust us it's good food but
it doesn't open till noon so I had like
half an hour in my car have to wait half
an hour in my car
so there's this Native Americans
monument near my house
it's called Montezuma castle it's on the
side of a cliff it's huge it's very big
and it was made a thousand years ago
1400 years ago and they made it and they
used to live there and then suddenly
they disappeared nobody knows why they
made many houses like this around my
house there are there are about a
thousand places smaller than this nobody
knows what happened to them I think
their air conditioners broke they went
someplace else anyway when I was a kid
you used to climb up there and now they
don't like they don't allow it no okay
but I had half an hour I never been
there I lived there for seven years it's
it's five minutes from my house I never
went there
so I said I'm gonna go look at it you
know and it's interesting because the
people are gone right who lived there
but the place is there and and the place
proves that there used to be people
there that's all so I I took a picture
of this place I put it okay
the place proves that the people were
there okay
and and in the refuge tradition we are
encouraged to be honest that we never
met Buddha okay are you do this yes
who's Buddha lived 2,000 years ago are
you sure I think so but you're a
Buddhist and you don't know if they live
or not yeah well
I don't know my mom said so because I
think like there comes a question in
Buddhism in Christian to Muslim you know
are you sure this person lived
you never did you meet them no do you
follow them yes okay then in Buddhism we
say I have jinkin gene I have seen gene
I have these beautiful teachings about
these four steps four powers four by
four five by four you know there is a
fight my father this is secret you know
and I have those teachings and and to me
they prove a person who was not like
anybody else in the world you know who
wasn't a copper animus okay there was a
person who came to this world and said
no it doesn't work that way it works it
differently you know the whole world
didn't believe it they caught copper
atom mist okay and then one person came
and said no that that's wrong that's not
how anything works it's not just wrong
it's completely wrong okay somebody told
me the first link in The Wheel of Life
is a lack of an understanding
no no no no no no no it's a
misunderstanding
okay it's not a lack of understanding so
bossy boiler will hit you on the head
two times if you say that you had Thomas
on it no I think God does when it's good
room
the other help no no the first leg is
not a lot of understanding its
misunderstanding okay
cotton copper atom is misunderstand
where the world comes from it's not that
they don't understand its opposite they
believe the opposite they believe you
can ignore a friend who's having trouble
with their husband or their wife and
your cell phone was still what they
believed in right got it that's
misunderstanding it's not lack of
understand got it
so one person came into this world your
world that you were born into okay and
one person came and said no that's not
the way it works one person against a
billion you know and and we're lucky
because people started to believe it and
they wrote down what he said and we have
those books and we have a tradition we
have a lineage okay and this village I
were literate
you're the next lineage Lama okay you
are I don't know forty three or
something like that you are the next one
something like I don't confuse me and I
can count them for you if you want but
you are the next one okay and you have
to keep it pure you have to keep it
you're okay two and a half thousand
years people didn't mess up this
explanation and if you mess it up you
first person in two and a half thousand
years okay yeah things coming from you
but you know not everything you know
then you just destroyed two and a half
thousand years is me so you have a big
responsibility in the monastery they say
you're not allowed to go to a teaching
unless you can take responsibility to
teach it again
yourself so Chinese people take notes
Americans don't I don't know I guess
Americans have better memory or maybe
they have the knowledge base I don't
know but you know it's your
responsibility to to pass it on
so how do we know there existed Buddha
jewel from the evidence we have okay
from the buildings they left okay you
can believe it so we will do that
meditation you can ask yourself you know
why do I believe in this person to who I
can't see I can't talk to them there's
no video there's a joke in Europe they
say Americans only believe something is
it in a movie
things like darts London oh my god so
you know we don't have video we don't
have photos but we have the teachings
okay so we can believe that there
existed this person okay now on the day
you see emptiness directly you will see
the Buddha directly you will need them
directly okay on that day you'll confirm
with director section what you deduced
from the evidence before okay different
experience then you can confirm there's
Buddha okay until then you are using
deduction but on the day you see
emptiness interesting you will meet the
would the Buddha didn't die Buddha still
there you can move them directly and you
will never be the same after that
okay you will never be the same after
that
by the way good news which relates to
your debate today is that you also see
both future Buddha self yourself on the
same day you see ahead and you can see
yourself become a Buddha already okay
and teaching and doing all these nice
things okay so on that day you can see
yourself as a you can see what you're
going to look like what you're going to
talk about okay you can see that okay
it's cool 500 years ahead okay you want
to go deeper or you want to go to the
bathroom let's go dig me for one minute
and as you're going to learn in debate
class today and the debate class will be
taught by Nick and Adam and my idea is
Katie and Aaron also okay because women
are better arguer than men are you know
that I mean all the men know that I'm in
it but there's an important form of
taking refuge which is called result
refuge okay it's called result refuge
you're going to learn five kinds of
refuge in debate class today okay you
can learn five different kinds one the
coolest one the fifth one is called
result refuge and it means you can do
prayers to a future Buddha named Mike
Milica dunya and turn okay Anton can
take refuge in a future Buddha called
Anton they will call your aunt owned by
the way because you have a nice name
okay okay got it
that the fifth kind of refuge to the
coolest one is take refuge in the future
Buddha called you and I give that I told
you sometimes I was having a hard day in
my dining business like very busy and
the boss is yelling I mean you know
calling me stupid probably I did do
something stupid you know and I feel
tired I feel sad and nervous too much
pressure then I would meditate but I
can't meditate in my office because I
built my office on a glass on purpose I
built it in the middle of the floor
I built it everybody can see what I'm
doing I'm the boss everybody can see
everything I'm doing and it helped the
whole company because they know I'm not
just relaxing they can see I'm doing
something so I built the office out of
glass and so I don't have any privacy so
I used to go to their toilets and close
it I do it number two okay in a boy's
bathroom it's more private and I go in
there I sit down I don't open the toilet
I just sit on the top then I'll say you
know to my future Buddha because future
Buddha can see all the past perm see so
I say hey my future Buddha - I'm having
a hard day you know and I got mad at my
boss you know I'm sorry I delayed you
because I got upset and I apologize it's
probably taken
for you to become Buddha and I just want
you to know I'm sorry
and I'm trying really hard who's going
to just having a hard day you know so
you can talk to your future Buddha
because they can hear you and that's a
special kind of refuge okay when you're
having a really hard day and you don't
have any friend to talk to and you can
talk to your future birth because they
are watching you right now and then like
come on 300